<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Bart Widlarz]]></title><description><![CDATA[A personal blog of Bart Widlarz.]]></description><link>https://widlarz.pl/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 22:29:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[One-On-One Meetings part 1, What]]></title><description><![CDATA[A 1on1, or one on one meeting is a basic, yet a crucial tool to facilitate
communication in your organization. It is achieved by regular…]]></description><link>https://widlarz.pl//1on1/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://widlarz.pl//1on1/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 22:09:25 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A 1on1, or one on one meeting is a basic, yet a crucial tool to facilitate
communication in your organization. It is achieved by regular, set up,
face-to-face meetings that usually last between 30 to 90 minutes each and even
though virtually anybody can set a one with anybody, we’ll focus on the one
between leaders and those who are being led. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is a 1on1 meeting and what is not&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each meeting may or may not have an agenda, though it should be stated
beforehand what kind of topics are preferable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/50d853662075643fb7599ee113166baa/30631/OneOnOne.jpeg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
  
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block;  max-width: 590px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 66.6875%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAANABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwABAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQBAv/EABUBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAB/9oADAMBAAIQAxAAAAGvYaTkWf/EABoQAAMAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECAwAREiH/2gAIAQEAAQUCZgC1vRZRkqHZ5yZ7X//EABURAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAS/9oACAEDAQE/AZS//8QAFxEBAAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEREv/aAAgBAgEBPwHS5f/EABoQAAIDAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAhEhMUH/2gAIAQEABj8ChJCxax8K8sdxL4f/xAAZEAEAAwEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABABEhMUH/2gAIAQEAAT8hC0bymECcjWUhOn2XatGCBmjLmazyp//aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQf9//xAAXEQADAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREh/9oACAEDAQE/EFikn//EABgRAAIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABESFh/9oACAECAQE/EHaDY//EAB0QAQEAAgIDAQAAAAAAAAAAAAERACFxoTFBsWH/2gAIAQEAAT8Q3le1iXjNGUIghPvWWBO5o98ZVCKk+zBQEOlO9YgugwEfH7M//9k=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;OneOnOne&quot;
        title=&quot;&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/50d853662075643fb7599ee113166baa/f8fb9/OneOnOne.jpeg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/50d853662075643fb7599ee113166baa/e8976/OneOnOne.jpeg 148w,
/static/50d853662075643fb7599ee113166baa/63df2/OneOnOne.jpeg 295w,
/static/50d853662075643fb7599ee113166baa/f8fb9/OneOnOne.jpeg 590w,
/static/50d853662075643fb7599ee113166baa/85e3d/OneOnOne.jpeg 885w,
/static/50d853662075643fb7599ee113166baa/d1924/OneOnOne.jpeg 1180w,
/static/50d853662075643fb7599ee113166baa/30631/OneOnOne.jpeg 1600w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Topics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the list of possible topics may become as long as my arm and depends on a
particular project or company, the list of undesirable ones is quite short and
is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;issues discussed while daily meetings in a group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;issues normally discussed during retrospective or similar meetings if applicable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;implementation or technical details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rumors*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems hard and fast, but the reality is that it might be okay to discuss these
topics if they affect interlocutors. Some would argue that the list should
include „rumors” of any kind, but on contrary, I can imagine a set of examples
where a 1on1 meeting might be actually a perfect place to discuss them alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;*Special case: rumors&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might happen that gossip comes up during a meeting, whether as the effect of
piping up or a deliberate maneuver. If it has already come up, then it ought to
be addressed. Moreover, if need be, let’s explicitly bring them up over the
course of a meeting to juxtapose them with facts and clean the air. These are
just examples of topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slanderous gossips, if one of you feel the urge to discuss them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gossips about employees leaving the company in bulk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;misleading rumors around a strategy of a company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that being stated, what kind of rumors should be omitted? Well, it depends
heavily on the reason behind mentioning them in the first place. There are
individuals who take a great deal of pleasure from gossiping, especially if they
happen to be in the face to face situation when nobody else listens to. So,
unfortunately, 1on1s are great for those who take sheer pleasure from gossiping.
I definitely encourage you to steer clear of it and to sort it out as soon as
you notice by weeding out a topic and replacing it with a valuable one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Who should be running them and why it should be a team leader&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The popular fallacy is that 1on1 is a mundane task to be  done by HR people and
in fact, there is at least one reason to think so, namely the identification of
flight risks among staff. While such issues may well be topics for 1on1 they are
merely the beginning and our definition of 1on1 should be extended by far more
items including measuring job satisfaction, discussing obstacles, clarifying the
mission of the project or explaining recent decisions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why having a team
leader or a manager to run those meeting is what is generally desired. It
demands a wider perspective, closer relationship and a piece of comprehensive
knowledge about one’s environment to run a valuable discussion that could end up
with actionable points.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello!]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is the first blog post here, I just wanted to say hello and put there some information about me. I’m a Software developer, Frontend…]]></description><link>https://widlarz.pl//hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://widlarz.pl//hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 22:11:51 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is the first blog post here, I just wanted to say hello and put there some information about me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a Software developer, Frontend &amp;#x26; Mobile creator, Team Leader, father and husband.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I help to build software products and services from the ground up, particularly Android and iOS native or React Native apps and frontend apps in React.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;building the team from scratch or mentor and introduce to React/React Native world a current team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;building processes, establishing CI/CD for mobiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apps deployment in general&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>